Giovanni Rossini

Bauru, São Paulo, Brazil

giovannirossini@duck.com

+55 14 982336349

linkedin.com/in/rossinigiovanni

https://giovannirossini.github.io

Summary

DevOps engineer with professional experience in large-scale environments using Linux and Unix, including design and installation of systems and services, configuration, sizing, automation, capacity planning, containers, docker, Kubernetes, networks, security, and integration in heterogeneous environments. I believe that teamwork is the key to achieving success in any organizational team.

Experience in programming scripts in Python and Shell, in developing applications for Linux and Unix platforms, creating pipelines, and automate tasks and processes.

Experience in monitoring mixed environments, including containers, virtual machines, appliances, and physical servers.

Skills: Amazon Web Services • Ansible • Azure • BrowserStack • Buddy Works • Continuous Delivery • Continuous Deployment • Continuous Integration • DevOps • Docker • Git • GitHub Actions • Golang • Google Cloud Plataform • Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) • Grafana • Infrastructure • Jenkins • Kubernetes • Linux • Microsserviços • MongoDB • New Relic • Node.js • Pipeline Development • Prometheus • Puppet • Python • Ruby • Shell script • SQL • Terraform • Windows server • Zabbix

Experience

site Reliability Engineer

Bees Brasil

Oct 2021 - Present (1 year +)

Azure and AWS cloud administration

Monitoring using New Relic for Alerts, Synthetics and Dashboard with provisioning using infrastructure as code with Terraform/Terragrunt

Environment automation tools with IaC using Chef and Ansible

Docker and Kubernetes container administration and configuration with Argo CD

Troubleshooting a complex environment using various tools like New Relic, Argo CD, FullStory, Azure

Monitoring, Mongo Atlas, Cloud AMQP, Amazon CloudWatch, UP Trends

Performing with MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, AppCenter, Azure DataFactory

CI/CD with Azure DevOps Pipelines

Script development using Python and Flask

Agile practices with Kanban using Jira

DevOps Architect & SRE

e-plugin

Oct 2019 - Present (3 years +)

Responsible for creating and maintaining Cloud environments on AWS.

- Build and maintain Docker
- IaC with Ansible. Terraform and CloudFormation
- CI/CD with Bitbucket Pipelines and Github Actions
- Shell and Python scripting

- Observability with Grafana, Prometheus, NetData and Cloudwatch Working with RDS, Cloudfront, Route53, ACM, ALB, WAF, S3, Opensearch Service, ElastiCache, ECR, ECS, EKS, Aurora, EC2...

G Site Reliability Engineer

Getnet Brasil

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021 (4 months)

SRE & DevOps Architect

TOTVS

May 2019 - Jul 2021 (2 years 3 months)

Responsible for creating, automating, managing, and maintaining the high-performance and available cloud environment.

- Responsible for implementing and maintaining CI / CD (Buddy Works and Github Actions)
- Development of scripts using Python and Shell
- Infrastructure automation using Terraform and Ansible focused on disaster recovery
- · Management of environment variables with Vault
- Create and maintain mixed environments, virtual machines, and Kubernetes, with Azure, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), and Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Create and maintain Cloud SQL, Storage, Network, Firewall, and DNS environments
- Create and maintain proxy's with HaProxy, NGINX, and Traefik
- Create and maintain monitoring environments with ELK and Stackdriver
- Create and maintain development structures using Docker (Docker and Docker Swarm)
- · Responsible for maintaining and propagating the culture of DevOps
- Support for teams to automate their tasks
- · Automation for QA's

DevOps Engineer

UOL

Oct 2018 - May 2019 (8 months)

Focusing on deployment and automation, in an environment of high performance and availability.

- · Continuous Integration Jenkis
- Infrastructure Automation Puppet and Ansible
- Automation Deployment & Orchestration Jenkins
- Container Concepts Docker
- Orchestration Kubernetes
- Cloud AWS.



Instituto Soma

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019 (4 months)

Contributing to the maintenance and improvement of pipelines, continuous integration and delivery. As well as in the project architecture using DevOps culture tools and concepts for continuous improvement of delivery and deployment processes.

Infrastructure Analyst

Ferragut Soluções em T.I.

Aug 2017 - Oct 2018 (1 year 3 months)

Working with:

- Windows Server (2008 R2, 2012, 2012 R2, 2016 e 2019 AD DS, AD LDS, AD FS, DNS, DHCP, NPS, TS, File Server, Print server);
- Linux (CentOS, Ubuntu Server e Debian nginx, apache2, fail2ban, Samba, iptables, OCS Inventory, Zabbix, Bacula, Grafana, Prometheus e Graylog);
- E-mail (G Suite e Office 365);
- PfSense (Roteamento, Firewall, VPN IPSec, OpenVPN, DNS, DHCP, Zabbix Proxy, Snort);
- Switchs (HPE, H3C, 3COM, Aruba e Cisco);
- Virtualização (VMWare ESXi 5, 5.5, 6, 6.5, 6.7 e 7- Hyper-V 2012 R2 e Server 2019);
- Bancos de dados (SQL Server 2016, MariaDB/mysql, Postgres11);
- Zabbix (Server, Proxy, criação de template com MIBs, integração com e-mail, Telegram);
- Storage (HPE, IBM e Dell);
- Servers (HP, Dell, IBM/Lenovo);
- Soluções de Backup (Veeam Backup & Replication 9.5, 10 e 11);
- Telefonia IP (Issabel);
- Service desk e boas praticas (ITIL V3).



DevOps Engineer & SysAdmin

Instituto Soma

Jul 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 3 months)

Responsible for creating and maintaining the AWS environment for our systems

- Create and maintain Dockerfiles
- · Create and maintain docker images
- Responsible for implementing CI / CD using GitLab
- Responsible for maintaining and propagating DevOps culture among teams
- Development of Python and Shell scripts
- Support for teams to automate their tasks
- Automation of everything possible
- Network management
- User management
- · Responsible for innovation and bringing new tools and technologies
- · Mixed environments such as Unix / Linux and Windows



Infrastructure and Network Trainee

Tilibra

Dec 2016 - Jul 2017 (8 months)

- · Intermediate server maintenance
- Server management
- · Network management

· Monitoring of networks and computers

Support Trainee

Tilibra

May 2016 - Dec 2016 (8 months)

- End-user, infrastructure-oriented support
- · Basic computer maintenance
- Helpdesk

Information Technology Help Desk Support

Grupo Multicobra

Aug 2015 - May 2016 (10 months)

- End-user support for the system used
- Development of SQL's
- · Administrative routines
- · Remote customer service
- HelpDesk

Telemarketing

Grupo Multicobra Aug 2013 - Jul 2015 (2 years)

Education



Universidade Paulista

Bacharelado, Ciência da Computação 2015 - 2018 I dropped out

Licenses & Certifications

DevOps Foundation

11906185

AWS na Prática

11907966

Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate - CertiProf

DevOps Essentials Professional Cetificate - CertiProf

Agile Scrum Foundation

13390888

- Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation Coursera 2BEQ9LXXGZEQ
- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Coursera
- Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services Coursera
- Elastic Google Cloud Infrastructure: Scaling and Automation Coursera
- Uncomplicating Kubernetes LINUXtips 32750208
- Uncomplicating Docker LINUXtips 23158448
- Uncomplicating Istio LINUXtips 32942906
- Container Expert LINUXtips
 37425821

Skills

Suporte para Help Desk • Redes LAN-WAN • Hardware • Grafana • Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) • GitHub • Buddy Works • DevOps • New Relic • BrowserStack